browserdefender.com 2017-12-24

# Privacy | Symantec

At Symantec, we protect the world’s people and information by conducting our business with a commitment to transparency and choice. We protect your privacy, so you can focus on achieving your goals.

Symantec Website Security and related PKI solutions are now part of DigiCert, Inc. [Learn more about DigiCert, Inc. Privacy Policy](http://www.websecurity.symantec.com/legal/privacy)

Last modified: February 8, 2016 (view archived versions)  

Download Privacy Statement

When it comes to your information, Symantec Corporation, and its group of companies (“Symantec”, “we”, “us”) are committed to transparency and choice. We protect your privacy, so that you can focus on achieving your goals. This Statement is designed to let you know what information we collect about you on our websites (“Your Information”) and how we use that information in accordance with our mission to make the world a safer place.

If you live in the European Economic Area, the Controller of Your Information is Symantec Limited, Ireland, which has its principal place of business at Ballycoolin Business Park, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland.

Symantec has been awarded [TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal](http://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/validation?rid=213efdf4-f261-4bcf-a3f6-9f421cac3957) signifying that this Privacy Statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact [TRUSTe](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through [www.Symantec.com](http://www.symantec.com/) and [www.Norton.com](http://www.norton.com/), and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site or mobile applications.

What This Statement Covers __

This Statement only applies to the personal information we collect through our websites and does not apply to information collected by or in connection with your use of our products and services. To learn more about the privacy practices relating to certain products or services, visit our “If You Use Our Products” Section.

Information We Collect __

When you visit our websites, we may collect or ask you to provide certain information in order to help us manage our relationship with you. This information may include:

  * Contact details, such as name, mailing address, email address and phone number;
  * Shipping and billing information, including credit card and payment information;
  * Your transaction history;
  * Information you provide to us to receive technical assistance or during customer service interactions;
  * Information about other people that you may provide with any program or services including Refer-a-Friend;
  * Information about your computer or device, including browser type and settings, IP address and traffic data relating to your Internet connection; and
  * Symantec product performance data and information about how you use our products and services.

How We Use Your Information __

### We May Use Your Information To:

  * Create and manage your Norton Account, when you purchase from our online store;
  * Create [MySymantec](https://mysymantec.force.com/customer/s/), when needed to access communications and services;
  * Verify your identity and entitlement to products or services, when you contact us or access our services;
  * Provide commercial quotes for our products and services;
  * Process your purchase transactions;
  * Update you on the status of your orders;
  * Allow you to register products or services you purchase;
  * Manage your subscriptions;
  * Provide you with technical and customer support;
  * Subscribe you to a newsletter, send product updates or technical alerts;
  * Communicate with you about and manage your participation in contests, offers or promotions;
  * Solicit your opinion or feedback, provide opportunities for you to test software;
  * Research and implement product improvements and product updates;
  * Evaluate and improve the quality of our products, services and websites;
  * Allow you to Refer-a-Friend who may be interested in our offerings, as permitted by law;
  * Provide you with a customized experience when you visit our websites;
  * Allow interoperability within our applications;
  * Secure our systems and applications;
  * Allow for the provisioning of services; and
  * Enforce our legal rights or comply with legal requirements.

### Marketing

**Messages**  
In addition to the purposes described above, we may, in compliance with applicable consent requirements, use Your Information to provide you with advertisements, promotions and information about products and services tailored to you and your needs. This may include using demographic data or trend data provided by third parties, where permitted. Contact details, including phone numbers and email addresses, may be used to contact you. If you do not want us to use Your Information in this way, you can simply choose not to give your permission on the webpages and/or forms with which we collect Your Information. Please note that in some regions this may involve un-checking a box. You can also exercise this right at any time by unsubscribing from promotional emails.

**Interest-Based Ads**  
We may provide information about your interests in our products to third parties for the purposes of serving you more relevant ads. Where we provide you with interest-based ads on a site other than our own, we do not track your other activities on that site. If you click on our ads, we will know only the domain you came from. For more information, please see the Tracking Technologies & Do Not Track section below.

**Information From Third Parties**  
Third parties may provide us with information about you from online and offline sources. We may combine such information with the information we already have about you in order to provide you with a better experience, determine your interest in our products or improve the quality of our offerings.

**Symantec Website Forums or Networking Sites**  
We operate forums, websites and related information services, to better assist you in using our products and services, discussing technical issues and sharing your experiences. You should be aware that any information you provide in these public forums will not be kept confidential, as it may be read, collected and used by others who access them. To request removal of Your Information from any forum, [contact us here](mailto:privacy@symantec.com). In certain circumstances, we may not be able to remove Your Information, in which case we will let you know why. Your use of these other services may be subject to additional terms and conditions.

Tracking Technologies and Do-Not-Track Cookies __

### Cookies

A cookie is a commonly used automated data collection tool. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or device by websites that you visit or HTML-formatted emails you open, in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently.

We and our partners may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, scripts or other similar technologies on our websites or emails to, among other things:

  * Tailor information presented to you based on your browsing preferences, such as language and geographical region;
  * Collect statistics regarding your website usage;
  * Provide us with business and marketing information; and
  * In some cases, to enable a third party to deliver future advertising for our products and services to you when you visit certain websites owned by third parties.  

We use different kinds of cookies:

  * **Essential cookies** are necessary to provide you with services and features available through our websites. Without these cookies, services you may need, such as shopping carts or e-billing, cannot be provided.
  * **Analytics or customization cookies** collect information that is either used in aggregate form to help us understand how the website is being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or to help us customize the website for you.
  * **Advertising cookies and tracking scripts** are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly delivered and, in some cases, featuring ads based on your interests. To opt-out of our cookies used for online advertising provided directly by Norton.com, [click here](http://dtmc.norton.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=2474&cname=Symantec%20-%20Norton&cmagic=0bf727&clogo=symantec.png&loc=us&lang=en).

If your website includes a cookie management tool, you will find a hover button at the bottom of your screen.

If you do not wish to receive cookies you may be able to refuse them by adjusting your browser settings to reject cookies. If you do so, we may be unable to offer you some of our functionalities, services or support. If you have previously visited our websites, you may also have to delete any existing cookies from your browser.

We gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We may combine this log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

### Do-Not-Track

There are different ways you can prevent tracking of your online activity. One of them is setting a preference in your browser that alerts websites you visit that you do not want them to collect certain information about you. This is referred to as a Do-Not-Track (“DNT”) signal.

Please note that our websites may not recognize or take action in response to DNT signals from Web browsers. At this time, there is no universally accepted standard for what a company should do when a DNT signal is detected. In the event a final standard is established, we will assess how to appropriately respond to these signals.

For more detailed information about cookies, Do-Not-Track and other tracking technologies, please visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

### Third Party Data Collection

This may also include cookies placed by third parties, to deliver tailored information and content which may be of interest to you, such as promotions or offerings, when you visit third party websites after you have left our websites. We do not permit these third parties to collect personal information about you (such as email address) on our site, nor do we disclose with them any personal information about you.  

### Social Media Features and Widgets

Our websites include social media features, such as Facebook’s “Like” button, and widgets, such as the “Share This” button, or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features are usually recognizable by their third party brand or logo and may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our websites, and set a cookie to enable the feature to work properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

How We Disclose Your Information __

We do not sell, lease, rent or give away Your Information. We only disclose Your Information as described below, within our group of companies, with our partners, with service providers that process information on our behalf and with law enforcement. Processing is only undertaken for the purposes described in this Statement. If we disclose Your Information, we require those we disclose it with to comply with adequate privacy and confidentiality requirements, and security standards.  

### Partners

We may provide Your Information to our partners for the sole purpose of allowing them to conduct Symantec business. Our partners go through a certification process and only after that are they authorized to promote and sell our products and services. Our partners may use Your Information to communicate with you and others about Symantec products or services.

If you do not wish to receive promotional emails from our partners, you can unsubscribe directly in the footer of the partner’s email to you.

### Service Providers Processing Data On Our Behalf  

We may use contractors and service providers to process Your Information on our behalf for the purposes described in this Statement. We contractually require service providers to keep information secure and confidential and we do not allow our data processors to disclose your information to others without our  
authorization, or to use it for their own purposes. However, if you have an independent relationship with these service providers their privacy statements will apply.  

### Law Enforcement  

In certain instances, it may be necessary for Symantec to disclose Your personal information to government officials or otherwise as required by applicable law. No personal information will be disclosed to any law enforcement agency or governmental agency except in response to:

  * A subpoena, warrant or other process issued by a court of competent jurisdiction;
  * A legal process having the same consequence as a court-issued request for information, in that if Symantec were to refuse to provide such information, it would be in breach of local law, and it or its officers, executives or employees would be subject to liability for failing to honor such legal process;
  * Where such disclosure is necessary for Symantec to enforce its legal rights pursuant to the laws of the jurisdiction from which such information was gathered;
  * A request for information with the purpose of identifying and/or preventing credit card fraud; or
  * Where such disclosure is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat of bodily harm to the data subject.

### Global Data Transfers  

Symantec is a global company and, as such, we process information in many countries. To conduct our business, and in accordance with this Statement, Your Information may be transferred to our approved partners, service providers, contractors, Symantec Corporation in the United States, or to subsidiaries of Symantec Corporation, which may be located in countries around the world. We will take steps to ensure the necessary level of protection is in place for these transfers, and all transfers will occur in compliance with applicable laws and regulations.

In the process of continuing to develop our business, we may acquire subsidiaries or other business entities. As a result of such transactions, and for the purpose of maintaining a continued relationship with you, we may transfer Your Information to a related affiliate. If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition or sale of our assets, Your Information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify you of any such deal and outline your choices in that event.

How We Protect Your Information __

We have taken appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect Your Information from misuse, unauthorized or unlawful access or disclosure, loss, alteration, damage or destruction. These measures include:

**Physical safeguards** , with locked doors and file cabinets, controlled access to our facilities and secure destruction of media containing your information.

**Technology safeguards** , like the use of Symantec anti-virus and endpoint protection software, encryption, and monitoring of our systems and data centers to ensure that they comply with our security policies. For example, credit card information is transmitted using Transport Layer Security (TLS) encryption.

**Organizational safeguards** , like training and awareness programs on security and privacy, to make sure employees understand the importance and means by which they must protect Your Information. Our organizational privacy policies and standards also guide our handling of Your Information.

**Storage of Your Information**  
The information we collect from you may be stored on servers in the United States and anywhere Symantec or our vendors operate.

**Links to Other Websites**  
Our websites may contain links to other websites, which are owned or operated by other companies. If you choose to visit any linked websites, we encourage you to review their privacy statements carefully, as they may differ from ours. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites that are owned by companies that are not within the Symantec group of companies.

Our websites may also link to co-branded websites that are maintained by Symantec and one or more of our business partners, who are collecting Your Information pursuant to their own privacy practices. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on any co-branded site to which you link for information on the privacy practices of that site.

**Children’s Privacy**  
Our site is not directed to, nor do we knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13.

Managing Your Information __

We retain Your Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We also retain and use Your Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. We store Your Information for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which we collect it.  

### Accessing, Updating or Correcting Your Information

You are able to view and update much of Your Information through your [Norton Account](https://login.norton.com/sso/embedded/login?service=https%3a%2f%2fmanage.norton.com%2f&detectAgent=1&displang=iso3%3aeng&displocale=iso3%3aUSA) or for enterprise customers, your [MySymantec](https://mysymantec.force.com/customer/s/). Under certain circumstances, you may be able to request the removal of inaccurate or incorrect information we have about you. We will respond to requests to access or delete Your Information within 30 days.

If you are a California resident under the age of 18, you may be permitted to request the removal of certain content that you have posted on our websites. To make such a request, please contact us.

### Contact Us  

If you have questions or concerns about your privacy, please:

**Write to us:**  
Symantec Corporation – Privacy Team  
350 Ellis Street  
P.O. Box 7011  
Mountain View, CA 94043  
U.S.A.

**Call us:**  
1-650-527-8000

If you are located in the European Economic Area, please:

**Write to us:**  
Symantec Limited – Care of the UK and Ireland Legal Team  
350 Brook Drive  
Green Park, Reading, Berkshire, England, RG26UH

Changes To This Statement __

We reserve the right to revise or modify this Statement. In such event, we will post a prominent notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. If the changes would have the effect of introducing a purpose for the use of Your Information that is inconsistent with this Statement, and where required by applicable law, we will either notify you or provide you with an opportunity to opt-out from Symantec making such use.
